Federico Rubino

2713 Princeton Court Marina 93933

831.588.7750 federico.rubino8@gmail.com frubino@csumb.edu

github.com/FedericoRubino https://www.linkedin.com/in/federico-rubino-4b7132184/



Skills and Attributes

I am proficient with a variety of construction tools. I am knowledgeable in Python, Java, C++ and Javascript and have a basic skill set in AutoCAD, Excel, Salesforce, SharePoint and Oracle Agile. I am fluent in English, German and Italian. I am calm and collected during any situation and have shown strong leadership skills throughout my work and social life. I have experience in teaching all aspects of science to students K-12 and above. I have shown on multiple occasions that I am great at resolving conflict and that I can adapt to learn in many work environments. I am also charismatic with coworkers and customers.

- Intermediate: Python, Java, C++, Excel, Android
- General: Javascript, AutoCAD, Salesforce, SharePoint, Oracle Agile
- Languages: English, German, Italian
- Calm, collected, teamwork skills, communication skills, conflict resolution

Experience

Poly/ Plantronics Inc. / QE Database Admin Intern

JUNE 2019 - DECEMBER 2019, SANTA CRUZ

At Poly I worked as a Database Admin, cleaning, managing and automating their legacy documents. This involved using python to automate the proper documentation of thousands of documents, while working with different tools such as Oracle Agile, Microsoft SharePoint and Salesforce. The internship at Poly made me proficient with many soft skills such as regularly leading meetings, writing many professional emails and presenting in front of a global team.

Environmental Science Workshop Watsonville / Enrichment Specialist

WINTER 2018 - SUMMER 2019, WATSONVILLE

At the Environmental Science Workshop it is my responsibility to mentor and teach elementary school students different science aspects. This ranges from all of the fields of science such as biology, chemistry, and physics. On a daily basis, I need to prove that I have a strong understanding of the sciences and the ability to convey this knowledge through projects and simple lectures.

Ashley Tile Inc. / Tile Setter

JANUARY 2014 - MAY 2018, BAY AREA

Throughout the years of working with Ashley Tile Inc. I have gained the trust and confidence from my employer to use, operate and drive highly valuable tools, machinery and materials (company truck, delicate tile and slab, etc.). On a regular basis I had the opportunity to be part of planning, designing and installing complex tile showers, floors and stairways, as well as worked on over 300 projects.

Felton Guild / Wedding Organiser staff

SUMMER 2013 - SUMMER 2016, FELTON

I catered food and drinks to up to 250 guests at a time, which taught me how to handle stressful situations with a collected mindset, for long periods of time. Soon my job there shifted and I was responsible for the entire venue including setup, cleanup, managing personal, and handling large quantities of money in addition to hosting events in a large scale.

Education

California State University Monterey Bay / CS Data Science

SUMMER 2019 - PRESENT, APTOS

At CSUMB I've taken courses in software design, Android production, Networking, Data Science and technical writing. This university has allowed me to work side by side with other aspiring computer scientist and has prepared me for the team dynamic

Cabrillo College / Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

SPRING 2015 - SPRING 2019, APTOS

Cabrillo is a special school with its diversity in teachers as well as teaching styles, which has given me the opportunity to learn from many types of mentors. This has made me a more well rounded individual. Going into engineering also has made me proficient in math and computer science. I have found a new love for learning at Cabrillo! I received Associate degrees in CS, EE, Math and Liberal Arts and Science.

Achievements

- 4.0 at Cabrillo College
- Traveled to and/or lived in over 10 countries
- Fluent in 3 languages
- Experience in the trades of tiling, demolition, hardwood flooring, plumbing, landscaping, and carpentry.
- Successfully finished multiple projects for tech companies.

More about me

After years of traveling back and forth between Europe and the United States, I've grown accustomed to learning and trying new things. I use my perception to gain a fresh look at similar situations, as well as a keen eye to adjust to new ones. I am passionate about the world we live in, so everything I do I give my absolute attention and wholeheartedness in order to make it a better place.

Strengths

- 1. Adaptable
- 2. Strong relationship builder
- 3. Fast learner
- 4. Goal achiever
- 5. Maximize projects to their fullest potential